$\left\{ \begin{array}{c} G \\ R \end{array} \right\}$ GIAN RIYANTO

Professional Summary

A software engineer with a strong passion for products, people, and building delightful user experiences. Driven by my intellectual curiosity and strong growth-mindset, I enjoy the process of collaboratively transforming new things I learn into meaningful contributions. I work best in a collaborative environment, decomposing high-level problems and designs into single lines of code.

Personal Info

+61406073200

☑ li.griyanto@gmail.com

gianriyanto.com

☐ linkedin.com/in/riyantogian

United States Permanent Resident Australian citizen based in Sydney

Experience

Software Engineer

LinkaAja Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

- Proposed and developed an automated data pipeline frameworks using Apache Airflow for improved efficiency and scalability.
- Implemented Direct Acyclic Graphs to schedule and monitor workflows - replacing previously manual and multi-step process.
- · Implemented data infrastructure processes to monitor data quality, ensuring production data is accurate and available for key stakeholders and business processes.

SAP SuccessFactors Jr. Consultant

Daya Dimensi Global Nov 2018 - Jun 2019

- · Configured SAP SuccessFactors projects based on the client's business process and requirements.
- · Gathered, analysed and transformed client needs, insights and problems into tailored system solutions.
- Expressed HCM best practices and related technological implementation.
- · Planned, designed, and executed systems integration testing to ensure systems perform in accordance to agreed requirements and customer expectation.

Product and Sales Analyst

EuroSoil Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

- Conducted and prepared product and customer research analysis for Southeast Asian market expansion.
- · Collaboratively delivered exceptional customer satisfaction through a well orchestrated end-to-end delivery of client Purchase Orders.
- · Participated in client sales meetings and delivered customer service duties throughout business delivery process.

Education

University of Technology Sydney

Mar 2016 - Oct 2021

Bachelor of Engineering and Diploma in Professional Engineering Practice (Honours) - Software Engineering

Technical Skills

ReactJS. Hooks

VueJS, Vuex

Node, Express

HTML, CSS, SCSS

JavaScript

Python

Git, Github

SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB

Airflow

Professional Skills

UI/UX Design

Agile Methodology, Scrum

Technology Consulting

Data Analytics

Machine Learning

Interpersonal Skills

Fast and Willing Learner

Inquisitive, Detail-oriented

Collaborative

Problem-solving

Software Projects

I OWE YOU

- Built and deployed a favours-debt-tracking web application using MERN technology stack.
- Worked mostly as a front-end developer designed, developed and delivered the client side application.
- · Received an honourable mention for its UI/UX design.
- Practiced writing clean, maintainable, and welldesigned code.

Teams Chat App

- A team communication channel and project management platform built using ReactJS, Node, and Firebase NoSQL database.
- Collaboratively worked with a team of 15 members using Scrum and Agile practices.

Analytics Dashboard

- Developed a responsive analytics dashboard for users to manage, monitor, and analyse data at a glance.
- Worked as a front-end developer designing and implementing the dashboard interface with VueJS and ChartJS.

Supervised Learning Project

- Implemented a machine learning classification algorithm to predict values of a dataset.
- Employed various data analytics processes, techniques and practices using python to improve efficiency, accuracy and performance.

Automated Data Pipeline

- Developed a data pipeline framework to automate previously laborious multi-step tasks using Python and Apache Airflow.
- Implemented Direct Acyclic Graphs to schedule and monitor workflows that is presently still maintained for various different business use-cases.

Relevant Coursework

Core Engineering Subjects

Design and Innovation
Business Requirements Modelling
Information Systems Development Methodologies
Systems Testing and Quality Management
Entrepreneurship and Commercialisation
Engineering Economics and Finance
Engineering Project Management
Mathematical Modelling 1 & 2

Computer Science Subjects

Advanced Internet Programming
Applications Programming
Data Structures and Algorithms
Introduction to Data Analytics
Database Fundamentals
Object-Relational Database
Software Engineering Studio 1A, 1B, 2A, 2B, 3A
Software Architecture

Other Experiences

Software Engineering Virtual Experience

JPMorgan Chase & Co Jun 2020 - Jun 2020

Programming Teacher Assistant

Code Camp Nov 2017 - Nov 2018

Mathematics Teacher Assistant

Montessori Mathematics Tutor Feb 2012 - Nov 2012